THIS PROGRAM CONTAINS AI-GENERATED CONTENT
[panting]
[♪ tense music playing]
[door closes]
[hammer cocks]
[grunting]
[breathing heavily]
[♪ theme music playing]
MURDER CLUB: LIAR'S TABLE
Oh!
You're the MASTER.
Huh?
Who's the MASTER?
- Aren't you the MASTER?
- My brother's the MASTER.
No. It's you, isn't it?
- Me?
- [Mr. X] Yes.
- I'm Mr. L.
- [Mr. X] Earlier,
it said in the news article
that one brother was taken to hospital
while the other fled.
"Phone scam gang on the run
got into a car crash."
"Technical mastermind seriously injured."
I was involved in an accident
where I injured my leg
while fleeing with my older brother.
HE WAS LIMPING WHEN HE WENT IN
BUT HE WASN'T WHEN HE CAME OUT
[Mr. T] You're saying
he's actually the MASTER, not Mr. L?
So Mr. L is the one who died?
WERE THE MASTER AND MR. L TWINS?
- [Mr. T] But--
- Here's what we know.
- Mr. L should have a limp.
- [Mr. X] Right.
But the person claiming
to be Mr. L right now
is faking a limp.
He's living under the identity of Mr. L.
One of my card clues
is a prison guard's testimony.
It said, "I heard two men
raise their voices."
- Two men were fighting.
- [Mr. X] Right.
They fought as if they wanted
to kill each other.
So I think the MASTER and Mr. L
fought over money,
and their lives ended up switched.
WHAT IS MR. L'S TRUE IDENTITY?
[host] It is time
for the private conversations.
We confirmed that we all
fired our guns at least once.
- I only fired once at the cabinet.
- [Mr. L] Right.
So I can't be the culprit, can I?
- The gun…
- We can't be sure of that.
Do you remember when you fired your gun?
It was at 00:25.
- [Mr. P] Yeah, it was around that time.
- Okay.
- What was it you took?
- [Mr. L] Why'd you shoot it?
We impersonate prosecutors and tell people
to check their account, right?
That phishing scam was my idea.
- I came up with it.
- Yes.
But we ran the scam so many times
that clients started to catch on,
so we needed a new idea.
The new ideas were in that cabinet.
New ideas? So you went to get the script--
To show it to the MASTER.
- [Mr. L] For the MASTER?
- While we escaped.
You must be pleased.
- [Mr. P] What?
- Never mind.
Then when you eventually
got to the control tower--
He was already dead.
- [Mr. L] He was dead.
- Yeah, that's right,
- when we were so close to escaping.
- [Mr. L] Yeah.
- We need to find who betrayed the MASTER.
- That's right.
- [Mr. X] I think--
- I think you're the traitor.
- Me?
- [Mr. X] No, that would be
- way too obvious.
- You think so?
[Mr. X] Yeah, that would be too easy.
I think it's Ms. H because--
You think it's Ms. H?
- [Mr. X] She really--
- It's not her.
I spoke to her,
and she said she's innocent.
She got a bit teary
and insisted it wasn't her.
What's your blood type?
- I'm type A, which means I'm very timid.
- [chuckles]
I don't have the personality
- to kill someone.
- Right?
- Yeah.
- I'm type A, too.
[Mr. X] That doesn't prove anything.
Here's why I think it's Ms. H.
She took the disk containing the VIP list
from the storage room.
CCTV CLUE 1
MS. H TOOK THE BACKUP DISK FIRST
She must have been planning
to do something with it.
- She didn't need the MASTER anymore.
- [Mr. X] Also…
I also think it's Ms. H
because she raised her gun
outside the gate…
- [Mr. X] Right.
-…but she didn't shoot.
SHE POINTED HER GUN
TOWARD THE CONTROL TOWER
When the gate opened soon after,
I think she went into the control tower
and fired her gun.
- She didn't need the MASTER…
- Right.
-…and got the disk--
- [Mr. L] She could put
a new team together.
And her younger brother
was scammed out of 150 million won,
- which is a huge amount of money.
- It is.
What do you think of Mr. T?
Right now, there's nothing…
We barely have any clues about him.
That makes him more dangerous.
It's either Ms. H or Mr. T.
It's one of those two.
We narrowed it down.
But I don't think you should
jump to conclusions
because we've only been here five minutes,
and you've already been swayed
- into changing your mind. [laughing]
- That's my weakness.
It sounds like
you might be on to something.
That darn Ms. H!
She's the culprit.
To start with, I think Mr. L
is spewing nonsense.
He's limping now,
but we saw on the CCTV
that his leg was fine.
- There is so much pointing at him.
- Way too much.
I think he talked off the cuff earlier,
not knowing so much evidence
would come out.
Look, he's limping! His leg is hurting.
My brother is actually the MASTER.
I hung him up.
There was a shot fired before.
I think that was me.
- And now, his lies are unraveling.
- [grunts]
He's being inconsistent.
So he's becoming the prime suspect.
The person I suspect is Mr. L.
ROUND 3 CARD CLUES
AI LOG, P'S NOTEBOOK, USB
MASTER'S TORN-UP NOTE,
PRISON VISITATION LOG
[host] The fourth shared clue
is the Goldilocks Zone.
[Ms. H] Goldilocks? What's that?
[host] The Goldilocks Zone
is the ideal shooting distance,
not too close, not too far.
That means someone in this zone
fired the fatal shot.
It's the viable range.
[Mr. T] Shall we take
a card clue from Mr. P?
- [Ms. H] Yes.
- We already have proof that it's not me.
I fired once at the cabinet.
- I'll take from one Mr. T.
- Okay.
MR. X TAKES ONE FROM MR. T
MR. T'S CARDS ARE SUDDENLY VERY POPULAR
- [Mr. T] There's evidence we missed.
- [Mr. L] Oh, yeah.
I really hope we find
something conclusive.
OBJECT CLUES COLLECTED
[Mr. T] Hey, look.
Mr. L keeps pretending to limp.
You don't need to do that.
- How rude to an injured person.
- [Mr. T] You don't need to fake it.
[Mr. P] It says here the system owner,
the server administrator,
changed from the MASTER to Mr. L.
THE MASTER WAS BLOCKED FROM THE SERVER
MASTER: ACCESS DENIED
I'll come clean. I'm not Mr. L.
I'm actually the MASTER.
- [grunts]
- So the MASTER isn't dead yet.
The one who died is Mr. L.
THE MASTER WAS PRETENDING
TO BE HIS TWIN BROTHER MR. L
MASTER
It's been really hard
pretending to be Mr. L.
I am actually the MASTER.
- What the heck?
- [Mr. X] The victim was Mr. L, right?
I'm the MASTER,
and my dead younger brother
is still hanging in the control tower.
- Who hung him?
- I must find the killer.
I hung him up,
but I'm not the one who killed him.
- [Mr. X] You sound like real siblings.
- [laughing]
HEHE
- Unbelievable!
- [laughing]
Who are you really? Darn it.
You would lose, Mr. P.
He's got fast reflexes,
so you can't beat him.
So you're the MASTER, not Mr. L?
Yes, I'm the MASTER,
which just proves I'm not the culprit
because my brother was essential to me.
What kind of scary person hangs up
and shoots an essential person?
[the MASTER] I'll explain the story.
Hear me out.
Don't tear up.
WAHH
- [all laughing]
- [Mr. P] Don't put on a show!
DISPLEASED
You mustn't attack him.
You'll face consequences.
- Who cares!
- He has fans around the world.
We need to catch the culprit!
My younger brother tried to kill me
because he was unhappy with his share.
So I had no choice but to restrain him…
[voice cracking] …and the server…
- [Mr. P] Why did your voice just crack?
- [Ms. H] Hey!
- [laughing]
- [exclaiming]
[Mr. T] You'll both get into trouble!
We're all in for it.
- We have to be careful.
- [Ms. H] Mr. L.
We wouldn't tease Faker like this.
I needed my brother to manage the system,
and there was a chance
I might fail to retrieve
the backup disk from the storage room.
So I had no reason to kill my brother.
I hung him up
and went to the storage room,
and I came back at around 00:36,
but he was already dead.
CASE TIMELINE
THE MASTER RETURNED AT 00:36
I looked for the backup disk but--
It wasn't there,
and it turns out she took it.
- [the MASTER] Yeah.
- [Mr. X] Why did you take it?
MS. H TOOK THE BACKUP DISK
FROM THE STORAGE ROOM AT 00:10
Now, it's my turn to explain.
I had a plan.
After the escape, I planned to set up
a two-person company with the MASTER
and take all of the profit.
Just you two? You planned to ditch us?
- I'm sorry, but--
- [Mr. T] Hang on.
What about everything we've done together?
Were we used and tossed?
- That reminds me of my wife.
- [laughing]
CRACKING UP
My goal was
to steal the backup disk
and use the VIP list on it
to found a new organization of my own.
I wanted to be queen.
SHE AIMED TO BECOME THE BOSS
OF A NEW CRIME NETWORK
I have another CCTV password.
Should we check it?
- I have one too.
- Let's go check.
I feel like we'll find something.
- [Mr. P] What's this?
- [Mr. X] It's the younger brother!
- [Ms. H] What?
- [Mr. P] The younger brother.
Mr. L!
[Mr. P] Yeah, that's Mr. L, right?
Who is that?
- He's my brother.
- It's Mr. L.
It's Mr. L, who we mistook for the MASTER.
- [Mr. P] His hands are cuffed.
- [Mr. T] The time was 00:20.
CASE TIMELINE
MR. L WAS ALIVE AT 00:20
CHECKING THE NEXT CCTV CLUE
- [Ms. H] Oh, my.
- What? This is…
- Who is that? Mr. X?
- Who's that?
MR. X IS LOOKING AT THE BODY
- It's Mr. X.
- Mr. X!
- Why is that me?
- He's still alive.
- He's alive.
- You're too handsome.
- [Mr. P] He just saw him and walked out?
- [chuckles]
Oh, I know what this is.
I told you I saw him hanging first, right?
He was already dead.
MR. L WAS TIED UP BUT STILL ALIVE AT 00:20
HE WAS DEAD BY THE TIME
MR. X ARRIVED AT 00:32
CASE TIMELINE
MR. L WAS MURDERED BETWEEN 00:20 and 00:32
CHECKING THE NEXT CCTV CLUE
Who is that?
- [Mr. X] This was at 00:30.
- [Mr. T] I think that's me.
- [Ms. H] It's Mr. T.
- Oh, right!
- He has a gun.
- Look at his face.
MR. T LINGERED BY THE SHOWERS AT 00:30
What is he looking at?
[Ms. H] What's that?
A GUN IN ONE HAND,
A PIECE OF PAPER IN THE OTHER
Oh, I think I know what that is.
It was on one of the card clues I picked.
It was some kind of formula
for calculating the ideal position
to successfully shoot the target.
[gasps]
[Mr. P] It's a mix of math and physics.
PROOF HE CALCULATED WHERE TO SHOOT FROM?
- I'll show you.
- Suspicious.
[Mr. X] Exactly.
- [Mr. X] Now the spotlight's on Mr. T.
- [Mr. P] Gosh, I…
[the MASTER] As you can see,
these are math equations.
It's a formula for calculating
where the shooter had to stand
in order to kill the MASTER.
[Mr. P] It's genius.
So Mr. T planned to kill him.
- But here's what I don't get.
- [laughs]
Who does the math
before pulling the trigger? [chuckles]
It makes sense if you want
to kill them on your first try.
Ordinary shooters
don't run calculations first.
Only artillerymen do that.
Stop changing the subject.
If you look here, the MASTER
is hanging, facing the showers by Gate 2.
The outer wall of the showers
is just outside the Goldilocks Zone.
MR. T WAS STANDING
RIGHT IN THE GOLDILOCKS ZONE
- I have something to say.
- [Mr. X, MASTER] Go on.
I'll tell you what time I fired my gun.
I pulled the trigger once too.
We saw you about to shoot, but you didn't.
[Ms. H] I heard the gunshot at 00:30,
and I fired my gun at almost
exactly the same time.
DID MS. H FIRE THE FINAL GUNSHOT?
CASE TIMELINE
FOURTH ROUND OF GUNSHOTS AT 00:30
Why did you fire? At what?
I didn't aim it at anyone,
I was just startled
- and took a shot.
- Where were you?
[Ms. H] I was by Gate 4.
[Mr. X] Oh, you were close to me.
I don't believe Ms. H because…
You fired into the air?
I fired as soon as I heard the gunshot
because I was so startled.
- I'll confess something.
- Go on.
None of you are even close
to catching the culprit,
and we're several rounds in,
so I'll share this.
I got sentenced 12 years, right?
I actually planned to kill the MASTER.
- Right.
- Because my life was over.
So I did plan to kill him.
The reason was because the MASTER
pinned his own crimes on me,
hence the long sentence.
That's why I got
a harsher sentence than I deserved.
I ended up taking
way too much of the blame.
So I had a grudge and planned to kill him.
I had it all planned out.
So I did shoot, but I missed.
I did the calculations
and I fired my gun by the showers,
but I messed up
because of my inexperience.
The fact that I did the math first
is proof that I'm a lousy shot.
- And handguns aren't all that accurate.
- That's true.
[Mr. T] I fired my gun
around the same time
Ms. H says she fired hers.
MR. T AND MS. H
WERE IN THE GOLDILOCKS ZONE
Did you really fire into the air?
- Yeah. I really did.
- I shot the air too.
You said you missed.
If that's true,
Mr. X is the only one
who could have killed
- after that.
- Why's that?
The bloodstain on the window
must mean the shooter was inside.
- I think that's the only explanation.
- [Mr. P] But the four gunshots
were fired before 00:21.
[the MASTER]
Four bullets were fired first…
CASE TIMELINE
SECOND ROUND OF SHOTS
He fired the four bullets then.
He must've killed my brother
when he first saw him.
No.
We saw four bullet marks in the wall
and I explained my route earlier.
It took around 30 minutes
to walk around the prison like this.
Were you looking for an extra gun
by any chance?
The extra gun was in your possession.
THERE WAS ANOTHER GUN IN THE LABYRINTH?
I'll take one from Mr. L.
DURING ROUND 1
FIREARM ISSUANCE LOG
NONE OF THE RECOVERED GUNS
MATCHED THE SERIAL NUMBER ISSUED TO MR. L
HE SAW THAT MR. L'S GUN
HAD A DIFFERENT SERIAL NUMBER
[gasps]
Oh! You're the MASTER.
FIGURED OUT HE WAS THE MASTER
AND NOT MR. L
WHAT HAPPENED TO THE DECEASED MR. L'S GUN?
[host] It's time
for the private conversations.
I was highly suspicious of Mr. L but--
- You don't think it's him?
- [Mr. T] No.
- Okay.
- [Mr. T] I think he's telling the truth.
THE MASTER WENT TO THE STORAGE ROOM
BETWEEN 00:19 AND 00:36
My prime suspect right now is Ms. H.
- Me too.
- It's because…
ME?
The victim died around the time
we both fired our guns.
We can't be sure,
but that's the most likely time frame.
I did plan to kill him but I missed.
And since I know it wasn't me…
But here's what I find suspicious.
Did you move around after the four shots?
I was moving around before that,
then I got startled and fired four times,
- then kept circling.
- But why?
Because I couldn't find my way.
That's why I circled the entire perimeter
before making my way toward the center.
I'm famously bad with directions.
I'm sorry to say this, Mr. X,
- but I don't think it's you.
- Thank you.
I think we can exclude you
from this discussion.
I don't want to be excluded.
I don't mean you should
stay out of the discussion,
just that we can rule you out
of the list of suspects.
I find it a bit odd
that Mr. X shot the wall four times.
I find it hard to believe
that he was just startled.
- [Mr. P] It doesn't add up.
- Yeah, that's a bit…
But by that logic,
you're the worst offender.
- Nothing you say adds up.
- Okay.
- Whether you're the culprit or not,
- [the MASTER] Yes?
do better in the real world,
even if you can shut down airports,
no matter how many fans
you have around the world,
you shouldn't live like that.
- Thank you. That's good advice.
- You've got to be credible.
You just keep changing your story.
GETTING SCOLDED A LOT TODAY
Anyway, for whatever reason,
he shot four bullets.
But in the case of Mr. T,
I noticed his eyes in the CCTV footage.
He looked like he was ready to kill.
You're telling me he didn't even
see where the bullet landed?
I can't make heads or tails of it.
Should we call Mr. T over?
- Yes, let's get Mr. T.
- I'll go get him.
You put your thinking cap on.
Okay, I'll have a think.
Mr. T, do you have a minute?
- [Mr. T] Me?
- [Mr. P] Yes.
[Mr. T] I actually wanted
to talk to Mr. L anyway.
- He's the MASTER, not Mr. L.
- Right, the MASTER.
- Hello.
- Hey.
- You said you missed.
- Yes.
- But you did try to shoot the MASTER.
- I did.
- I was trying to kill him.
- [the MASTER] Yeah.
You killed him?
No, I didn't kill him. [laughs]
- I attempted to.
- Oh, you tried.
There aren't enough chairs.
- It's okay. I'll get up.
- No, sit down. It's fine.
A CONSIDERATE GROUP OF CRIMINALS
Based on the timeline,
you moved way too quickly.
- You're basically Quicksilver.
- No, I moved the slowest.
No, you're Quicksilver. You zoomed around.
I'm the youngest here.
I'm 22 years old,
and I was a K-pop trainee.
They make you dance five hours a day,
so running is no problem.
Still, no one can move that quickly.
I'm of two minds right now,
because I want to believe
you shot four bullets by accident.
You saw there were
four bullets in the wall.
It's not like I fired
whenever someone passed by,
as if checking them off one by one.
"Oh, look. There's Mr. P." Bang.
That would be silly.
- Yeah, it was consecutive.
- [Mr. X] Yeah.
It is whatever you make of it.
But you moved back and forth so much,
- so the timeline--
- I went all around the prison.
Yeah, so I just wanted
to check that timeline.
I'm only telling this to you…
- Yes?
-…but I don't suspect you.
- My main suspect is Mr. T.
- Why's that?
He did the math
before he pulled the trigger.
He said that was proof
he was a lousy shot,
but if that were true,
he'd have fired more than once like you.
That's true.
The fact that he did the math means
he knew exactly what to calculate and how.
- He also got the longest sentence.
- [Mr. X] He did.
[Ms. H] I think that means
he was guilty on many fronts.
When you had the gun in one hand,
what was the note in the other?
Do you remember
I mentioned a password earlier?
- Yeah.
- Actually, it was the Pythagorean Theorem.
From the showers, you must shoot
diagonally at the control tower.
It's the formula to figure out
that diagonal length.
THE NOTE HAD CALCULATIONS
OF THE SHOOTING DISTANCE
I was trying to kill him
and I had a motive.
But I missed. So I actually wanted
to talk to the MASTER a bit more
because I think
Ms. H is really suspicious.
Mr. L died around the time
I fired my gun.
I'm almost certain it was at 00:30.
- You're right.
- Yeah.
And the two people who fired
at that time were me and Ms. H.
I told you I missed,
so it had to be Ms. H.
Earlier, she said
she shot at the air
because she was startled,
but I don't think that adds up.
I suspected the MASTER at first.
- I thought he killed him then went back.
- [Mr. P] Me too.
But now I'm certain
that Mr. L died at 00:30.
CASE TIMELINE
FOURTH ROUND OF GUNSHOTS AT 00:30
So from your point of view,
the two prime suspects
must be me and Ms. H.
I'm dead certain it's Ms. H.
That's what I think
because I know it isn't me.
Gosh, that means Ms. H is a scary lady.
[Mr. T] That's just my opinion.
ROUND 4 CARD CLUES
SERVER SYSTEM LOG, VOICEMAIL,
APPEAL DISMISSAL
COURT JUDGMENT,
MATERIALS STORED IN CABINET
[host] The final shared clue
is the control tower
glass fragment analysis report.
[Mr. T] So the glass was bulletproof.
The Goldilocks Zone
is between 25 m to 50 m.
If the MASTER was shot to death,
it had to be one of the two bullets
that were fired at 00:30.
- One of the two.
- Then it had to be Mr. T or Ms. H
- if it was 00:30.
- Let me just say this.
As I tried to explain
before we got this clue,
I'm certain Ms. H is the culprit.
- Why?
- [Mr. T] She lied about her gunshot.
We've now established
that Mr. L died at around 00:30.
We're the two people
who fired at that time.
But my bullet missed the mark,
so that leaves Ms. H.
- But my file says I shot into the air too.
- You're lying.
What if there was a surprising twist?
The MASTER tied him up, right?
- [Ms. H] Yeah.
- After injuring him.
What if Mr. P sprinted
to the control tower,
flung the door open,
and beat him to death with his fists?
Who, me?
Did you bump your head or something?
- Couldn't that be it?
- [Mr. T] We saw earlier--
It says he was shot to death.
What are you on about fists?
Where did you shoot from, Ms. H?
I'm a bit baffled
because it doesn't say here
that I shot anyone.
It says I shot into the air.
Well, we can't check your file
to see if that's true…
- Right.
-…so we can't believe you.
I'm just surprised we suddenly
narrowed it down to two suspects.
It's just my opinion.
Why don't the three of us
just go over there and drink coffee
while the two of you reach a compromise.
Or just play rock paper scissors.
I'm not willing to compromise
because I'm certain it's Ms. H.
IS THE CULPRIT MR. T OR MS. H?
Why did you kill him, Ms. H?
How will you make money after you escape?
I think it was Mr. T.
- We're in the same situation.
- Why did you kill him? Why did you lie?
This doesn't make any sense.
Why am I the one under suspicion?
- That's just how life is.
- [Mr. T laughing]
- It can be unfair and frustrating.
- [Ms. H] But we--
I didn't expect this from you, Ms. H.
Let's leave the case unresolved
and go get dinner.
IS THIS HOW IT ENDS?
- No one's owning up.
- [Ms. H] This is hard.
- Shall we vote on the menu?
- Sure. What should we eat?
- Pork belly!
- [Ms. H] Pork belly, of course.
At 00:35, Mr. X and I
faced each other at gunpoint.
- [Mr. X] Inside the control tower.
- When was this?
- [Ms. H] At 00:35.
- In the control tower?
- Why?
- This is new information.
- So I--
- I'll explain.
It says here
I arrived first at 00:32, right?
I saw that the MASTER was dead
-and realized there was a traitor…
- [gasps]
…so I pulled my gun out
and stood on guard.
That's when Ms. H suddenly appeared.
So I was like, "What the heck?"
"I'm going to shoot!"
That's what happened.
MR. X AND MS. H HAD A STANDOFF
IN THE CONTROL TOWER AT 00:35
CASE TIMELINE
MS. H ARRIVED AT 00:35
Tell us what you were doing
between 00:25 and 00:35.
- Yeah, tell us again.
- Sure.
- Then can we hear everyone's alibis?
- You go first.
I'll tell you in detail.
I headed to the showers at 00:15.
I heard the second round
of gunshots at 00:21.
- That was me.
- [Mr. T] It was Mr. X firing four times.
Between 00:21 and 00:23…
- [Mr. X] You were doing the math?
- [Mr. T] Yes, I was looking at the note
and I did take a shot
- from what is the Goldilocks Zone.
- [Mr. X] Okay.
I did pull the trigger.
But as I said earlier, needing a formula
as I'm such a lousy shot, I missed.
As soon as I fired,
I heard another gunshot.
I'm assuming it was Ms. H's gun.
I arrived at the control tower at 00:45.
Three people were already there.
There were three people at 00:45.
That must have been me and--
Me and Ms. H.
CASE TIMELINE
MR. T ARRIVED AT 00:45
When did you arrive, Mr. P?
Good question.
Walk us through--
Don't flash your file around.
A MAN WITHOUT ANY SECRETS
[Mr. P] I got there at 00:55.
Four people were there already.
- [Mr. T] So you were the last to arrive.
- Yeah, I got there last.
It took me 32 minutes
to circle the entire prison.
So what on earth were you doing
that it took you 55 minutes?
Oh, yeah.
I'm not one to run
even if I'm in a real hurry.
Oh, you walked?
I'm a country boy.
So even when the clock is ticking,
I move at a leisurely pace.
HE HAD TO COLLECT
THE INVESTIGATION RECORDS
AND NEEDED TO TAKE DOWN ALL THE MEMBERS
SO HE ARRIVED AT THE CONTROL TOWER LAST
There's a note
that I didn't disclose before.
This is Mr. X's mobile phone.
It shows he held
a grudge against the boss.
I think you should all take a look.
- [Mr. T] He has motive too.
- [Ms. H] Yes, a very clear motive.
- But the motive doesn't matter.
- [the MASTER] He's right.
- We all had a reasonable motive.
- [Ms. H] Yeah.
- What matters is our whereabouts at 00:30.
- [Mr. T] Yeah.
We need to find the killer,
and he died at 00:30…
00:30 is right, isn't it?
That's when Mr. L died.
We all believe he fired
those four shots, right?
So we can strike Mr. X off the list.
As for Mr. P and the MASTER,
we saw proof that the MASTER
saw Mr. L alive before 00:30,
and there's physical evidence
proving Mr. P's alibi.
So our focus should be
on whether the victim
was shot by me or Ms. H.
It had to be one our bullets.
It's the only explanation.
But that's only if he was
shot from the outside.
What? He was shot from inside the tower?
I think whoever shot him
would have left and come back later,
- as if it was their first time entering.
- Exactly.
It's like when you play Among Us,
you kill then run like hell.
I agree. Someone lied earlier.
They went to the control tower twice
and killed Mr. L the first time.
[Mr. P] Yes, it's from the inside.
So someone shot him at 00:30,
left the tower, then returned at 00:45?
That's the most likely…
I think that would be
too difficult to pull off.
What's difficult about it?
Shoot, leave, and come back in.
Who do you think is guilty, Mr. L?
I think Mr. X.
To start with, Mr. X found the body first.
- Why are you suddenly accusing Mr. X?
- [Mr. T] It can't be Mr. X.
I think it is Mr. X.
- You said you had a standoff.
- [Mr. X] Yeah.
[the MASTER] The person who was
in the tower at 00:30 was Mr. X.
Why did you do it, Mr. X?
I didn't.
He says it's not him, so there you go.
The fact that he fired so many shots
and where they landed--
The consecutive shots are a lie?
The evidence points to four rapid shots,
but it doesn't sit right with me.
I think he fired those four shots
to shake off suspicion
and used another gun to…
The fact that he is
bringing up another gun…
- He went to find another gun.
-…suggests that Mr. L…
No, the MASTER had another gun.
[Mr. T] Let me just say this.
If he had used another gun,
we'd have found evidence
proving there was another gun
with X amount of bullets remaining.
But there's no such evidence,
so I think we can dismiss that theory.
What matters most right now
is the direction you shot from.
If we can't determine the direction
Mr. X was shooting from,
the most plausible scenario
is that Ms. H is lying.
- [Mr. X] Can I share my theory?
- But I'm not lying.
Mr. T and I have the exact same alibis,
but he keeps accusing me.
So I think it's him
since he keeps trying to pin it on me.
It's a very risky move
to rule out everyone else
and say that it can't be me,
so it must be them.
To everyone else,
it's a fifty-fifty toss-up.
So I made a big gamble.
If the shot was fired inside,
we would have heard it.
But we heard all the gunshots,
and the CCTV confirmed
the shooters, locations, and times.
Something's not clicking
because the culprit
has no choice but to lie,
- so that's what they're doing.
- Right.
[Mr. T] And we believed them,
which is why it's not making sense.
And I think the liar is Ms. H.
Mr. L was alive between the first
and second round of shots.
And the gunshot at 00:25
was aimed at the cabinet.
We know he was shot to death,
so it had to be between the fourth
and fifth rounds of fire.
Then it really must be me.
[host] The final round is over.
Please make your closing arguments.
I was ruled out as a suspect
from the very start,
so I'm really happy about that.
I'm confident the shot was fired
from the inside
because I doubt anyone could
aim accurately from such a distance.
If the shooter was outside,
only the victim would know their location,
but if the shooter was inside,
they would very likely
run into someone while fleeing the scene.
I don't think the shooter
would take that risk.
I think it was Ms. H.
We saw her lowering her gun
in the CCTV footage.
She just couldn't get a clear shot
from the dining hall.
So she sprinted to the tower,
killed him, and left.
That's why the culprit is you.
- [in English] Goodbye!
- [Ms. H, in Korean] Am I the killer?
If we go by what Mr. T said,
it has to be me or Mr. T.
We both think the other did it.
Our alibis our similar,
but one of us is the culprit?
I don't think that adds up.
I think Mr. X did it.
I find it really suspicious
that he moved around so much.
And shooting four times in a row
is such a foolish thing to do.
Ms. H insists she shot into the air
because she was startled,
but that's a lie.
She fired the shot that killed Mr. L.
I think that's the only
plausible explanation.
Ms. H is the culprit.
VOTING COMPLETE
[host] Here are the voting results.
The MASTER got zero votes.
Mr. P got zero votes.
Mr. T got zero votes.
Ms. H got two votes.
Mr. X got three votes.
Mr. X got the most votes.
- [exclaims]
- [Ms. H exclaims]
You people are dense!
[host] The selected player shall open
the ending box bearing their number
and read the ending scenario aloud.
I have a feeling it's not Mr. X.
"He's a scapegoat."
"You failed to catch the culprit."
"The other members' key secrets
were kept hidden to the end."
"The escape plan, revolvers, and scapegoat
were decided from the start."
"Someone has to take the fall."
"Now, he gets what they meant by that."
"Mr. X eventually gets arrested."
"The investigation record stated
he was a low-level operative
who fired in a panic
while trying to escape."
"Mr. T quietly slipped away,
with no one catching on
that he was the shooter…"
THE CULPRIT WAS MR. T
"With no one catching on
that he was the shooter…"
[laughs]
Ah, damn it.
- She cursed! [laughs]
- [Mr. P laughing]
IT JUST SLIPPED OUT
I got chills.
CHILLING
[Mr. X] "After securing part of the funds,
he fled overseas."
Mr. T fled overseas?
Mr. Take-off.
"Mr. L's identity was never revealed.
He watched it all play out
from a distance.
After cutting loose one of their own,
he quietly planned his next move."
[Mr. P] Gosh, what a scary guy.
"Ms. H quickly got her cards in order."
"She didn't get to be a queen,
but she stayed in the game."
[Mr. T]
She wanted to become a female boss.
"Mr. P's ending."
"With Mr. X convicted as the culprit,
his ten-year undercover operation
was deemed a failure."
[gasps]
[Mr. X] "The organization was exposed,
but the true masterminds got away."
- Oh, you were an undercover cop.
- [Mr. P] I was undercover.
My wife was a victim
- of this kind of phishing scam…
- [gasps]
…so I wanted to take you all down.
I told you earlier that someone was lying.
That was me.
I said I missed because I got nervous.
That was the lie.
I didn't miss.
Yeah, I told you it wasn't me!
- What does it matter now?
- I mean,
I couldn't confess that I was the killer.
Hey, this is pretty major.
Because this log is just
the ledger of the money
we made from our scam.
- That's all it is. You need to see this.
- Okay.
Yeah, that's when I zoned out.
It really doesn't say what I did.
PRETENDED TO LACK INFO
But as I said earlier, needing a formula
as I'm such a lousy shot, I missed.
We barely have any clues about Mr. T.
[Mr. P] I know, Mr. T…
THERE WAS A LOT OF CONCLUSIVE EVIDENCE
Oh, I think I know what that is.
[Ms. H] What's that?
[the MASTER] It was some kind of formula.
MR. T WAS IN A PICKLE
I think Faker is on to me.
He looked at me suspiciously.
I thought I'd been caught for sure.
I don't have a very good poker face.
We didn't catch the culprit last time.
- You don't need to today.
- Why not?
- Because you're the culprit.
- Why me? [chuckles]
You traitor. [chuckles]
What are you on about?
I thought I was caught,
but I think my strategy
of putting the spotlight on Ms. H
was a really effective move.
Where did you shoot from, Ms. H?
Why did you kill him, Ms. H?
Why did you lie?
Why am I the one under suspicion?
[Mr. T laughs]
[Mr. P] That's just how life is.
He shared so many clues
that it threw me off his tail.
I was so sure
the shot was fired from inside
that I ruled him out.
I'm confident the shot was fired
from the inside.
KNOWINGLY SHAKING HIS HEAD
Mr. T played it well.
We were in the same boat
but he turned all the focus to me,
so fair play to him.
I started doubting myself!
That's how convincing his act was.
You're so annoying.
- You cleverly got away with it.
- [laughs]
I dropped a lot of hints. I really did.
I feel like we were so close.
- This game is really hard.
- [Mr. P] It's so hard.
I think this was the hardest one yet.
Even though I'm the culprit, I thought,
"Wait. Did someone else do it?"
- [laughing]
- Seriously, I started doubting it was me.
FINAL THOUGHTS
It's such a fun program,
and playing the game
with such smart, young people
has made me feel 20 years younger.
It was a really meaningful experience.
I hope after watching the last episode,
the takeaway will be
that scammers don't get a happy ending.
- We're all scammers, right?
- Yeah.
I hope all scammers get locked up.
I've never really played
board games before,
especially a game like this one
that's so immersive and high-quality.
I had so much fun
that the time just flew by.
And I really enjoyed getting to play
with such great people.
I also really enjoyed
getting to play a board game like this.
I was determined
to solve a lot of mysteries,
so I'm a bit disappointed
I didn't do that well.
But everyone really gave it their all,
so I had a really fun time.
I thought I was the best at this game,
but…
The more we find out,
the more I realize I'm the worst at it.
It was an eye-opening experience for me.
And it was an honor to play
with such distinguished people.
Thank you.
- Great job, everyone.
- All right.
- Good job.
- Great job.
- Good work.
- Good job.
THE FULL STORY
[♪ dramatic music playing]
00:00, THE LABYRINTH PRISON DOORS OPEN
[panting]
00:10, MS. H ARRIVES AT THE STORAGE ROOM
00:15, THE MASTER AND MR. L
SHOOT EACH OTHER, 1ST ROUND OF GUNSHOTS
[panting]
[gasps]
00:21,
MR. X FIRES THE 2ND ROUND OF GUNSHOTS
00:25,
MR. P FIRES THE 3RD ROUND OF GUNSHOTS
00:26, THE MASTER ARRIVES
AT THE STORAGE ROOM
00:30, MR. T AND MS. H
FIRE THE 4TH ROUND OF GUNSHOTS
00:32, MR. X FINDS MR. L DEAD
[Ms. H breathes shakily]
00:55, ALL MEMBERS ARRIVE
AT THE CONTROL TOWER
Translated by Hannah Og Nam